Episode 9
The Misanthrope and the Heart's Deepest Desire
Director's Office
What do you think of the advanced class?
It hasn't been without its trouble,
but things have settled down
since Ohgami decided on her career path.
That's good.
Now it's your turn, Haneda.
Me?
Yeah.
What do you want to do
after you become human?
Make music, I suppose.
Really?
I'd say I'm about half-serious.
And the other half?
I want to live life
like you do, Mr. Hitoma.
Are you messing with me?
You've got plenty
to enjoy in life, don't you?
Indulging your passions into the night.
Don't say it like that!
I'm just going to play video games!
I want to create things
that I love, just like you do.
There may be setbacks,
but I know they'll help me grow kinder.
Just like you, Mr. Hitoma.
I wouldn't call myself very kind.
Sure you are.
In my eyes, you come off as very human.
What does "human" even mean here?
How you're not perfect.
Mr. Hitoma, have you ever gotten angry?
Yeah.
Any bad memories?
Plenty of them.
What about happy ones?
Plenty of those, too.
Painful memories?
Lots of them.
Times you've given up?
I give up on something every day.
Times you've been sad?
More than I can remember.
There are all sorts of emotions
that have brought color to your life.
All of them are what
make you who you are now.
I have plenty of things I regret, too.
Say, Mr. Hitoma.
What is it?
If you could face your regrets,
would you give them your best?
What's that mean?
Just a hypothetical.
Would you rather forget your regrets?
Or face them head-on?
Well...
If I could do everything over...
I'd want to face them... I think.
I see.
Mr. Hitoma, you've grown stronger.
It'd be nice if that was the case.
It's time once again
for the advanced class final assignments.
To graduate and become human,
you'll have to pass your final assignment.
Everyone gets a different assignment.
Please give it your all.
How come I'm the only
one who got this big box?!
What is that?
My final assignment.
It's shattered into pieces.
Machi broke it because
she's rash and reckless.
She's already failed her assignment.
Nuh-uh!
My assignment is
to repair this with kintsugi!
Oh, they have assignments like that?
What about you, Uchami?
I have to write letters
to everyone in the advanced class.
What? That's a piece of cake!
You'll be done writing that in no time!
Not fair!
Be a little more serious.
Even if I write down whatever,
it won't be graded well.
Guess you're right.
On top of the final assignment,
I need to study to get into med school.
I have so much on my plate.
You even have Mr. Hoshino
helping you study after school.
What's the assignment for you two, Ohgami?
A-As for me...
I need to write reviews for ten works,
which include novels, comics, and essays.
Ten of them?!
The Tale of Genji, Kafka's Metamorphosis,
and much more, even American comic books.
What'd you get as an assignment, Ryuzaki?
I have to take on the dorm
mother Ryouko's work for ten days.
Really? That sounds rough.
I hear Ryouko will be away for ten days.
I'll be taking over during that time.
So you have to cook for the dorms?
There's more to it than that.
She also looks after the beginner class,
not to mention cleaning, laundry,
all sorts of small tasks...
And dealing with whatever
problems pop up, too.
Sounds like a heavy workload.
I wonder if I'll be able to handle it.
You'll do just fine, Karin. Good luck.
Thank you, Tobari!
I'll think of it as practice
for when I marry Mr. Rei!
S-Sure...
What's your assignment, Tobari?
I have to make a musical
instrument by hand.
A musical instrument by hand?
What are you going to make?
That's a good question.
You haven't decided yet?
Nope, but I think it'll be fun.
That's looking pretty big.
What are you making?
An electric guitar.
I was thinking of making it a Les Paul.
Can one person even make
an electric guitar?
They sell guitar necks
with the frets and all,
as well as parts like pegs,
bridges, and all the circuitry.
I see. It's totally beyond me!
This sure is a squeaking pain.
Traditional craft? More like a puzzle!
Shut up, Machi!
Squeak! Tobari's woodworking's
way louder than me!
That's part of her assignment,
so I don't mind it.
Hey! Stop playing favorites!
Looks like Ohgami's busy reading.
What's that you're reading, Ryuzaki?
A manual for performing
dorm mother duties.
Ryouko wrote down all the important parts.
Ryouko's as reliable as ever, I see.
Shiranui High
Student Dorm Manual
She even wrote down tips for dealing
with all of the beginner class students.
All the students at this school
are way too quirky!
You're pretty quirky yourself, Ryuzaki.
Your guitar's really starting
to take shape after a week.
Mr. Hitoma, listen to this!
Karin's such a meanie!
Give her a good lecture!
Hey, Machi. Crying
to Mr. Rei is playing dirty.
What happened?
She won't let me have seconds when I eat!
What?
The budget doesn't allow for it.
I can't go against the rules.
Isn't it your job
to make all of that work out?
You're a no-good crooked magistrate!
Shut up already!
Usami?
I-I'm sorry.
Don't mind me.
You just took me by surprise...
It's my fault.
Usami!
Sorry, Haneda.
Wrap up the rest of class for me.
Got it!
Mr. Hitoma.
Ms. Karasuma.
Usami's in the nurse's office.
Usami.
I'm awful.
I get annoyed easily.
I have angry outbursts.
I made Isaki cry...
I'm sorry. I was the one making
the most trouble in class.
It's fine.
What's fine about that?
Everyone has times when dealing
with others gets to be too much.
I know that.
That's right.
You'll feel calmer
after a nice, warm drink.
It's good.
Glad to hear it.
I'll apologize when I go back
to the classroom.
Yeah.
I'm sorry I didn't warn them
about being too loud.
Yeah, you should be.
Looks like you're feeling a bit better.
Usami.
Thanks for putting
the nurse's office to good use.
I'm always here, so feel free
to drop by whenever you need.
Haruka, why'd you decide
to become a school nurse?
I wanted to give people
a place to run away to.
A place to run away to?
You get people like that,
who work a little too hard.
Don't look at me like that.
It's always better to have
more places you can turn to.
Advanced Class
What? Stop staring at me.
I see you're working on your
assignment instead of studying.
Making good progress?
I'm not cut out
for this kind of assignment.
It should have been
a writer like Isaki who does this.
Isn't the point of the assignment
for you to get over not being good at it?
I know that already.
I was complaining,
not asking for an explanation.
How about you, Machi?
I'm glad you asked.
Believe it or not, today will be the final
step for my dear Bowledoodle!
Huh? Bowl-a-what now?
Bowledoodle!
The name of the bowl
I've been looking after!
Looks like Ohgami's struggling.
There we go!
I think I'm all done!
You really made a guitar?
The wood grain looks so cool.
This is my first time seeing
an electric guitar in person!
You play that thing really well, Haneda.
Really?
Thanks, Mr. Hitoma.
I'm off to go submit it to the principal!
It's so cool that she can play
an instrument.
Mr. Rei, do you like girls
who can play instruments?
Oh, it's more that I respect
people who are multi-talented.
I see. I learned something new!
Thanks, Mr. Rei! I love you!
Again with the immoral displays.
You're working hard, too, Usami.
I'll do it since I've been asked to.
But Isaki must be a real masochist
to do this every day.
Wh-What?!
E-Excuse us.
Oh? You're from the beginner class.
Karin! Thanks for everything
over the past ten days!
Thank you!
Th-Thanks...
Oh! Those are so cute!
They asked me to teach them
how to make icing.
So this is what they were trying to make.
I didn't get to see it, but looks
like you did just fine as dorm mother.
Yes, of course.
Nezu, how's your assignment going?
Squeak! I-I'll submit it sooner or later.
Didn't you say you were
on the last step yesterday?
How come you remember that?
Don't click your tongue at me!
But once I submit it,
Bowledoodle's gonna be gone!
Huh? You usually get to
keep it afterwards.
Wait, really?
Yeah. I got to keep this guitar.
Well now I feel stupid
for worrying so much.
How's it going, Ohgami?
W-Well, I do have a good
deal of it sorted out...
What's up?
I wonder if these reviews are good enough.
I can't help but worry that
I may have misinterpreted something.
Everyone gets something
different out of art.
You should write down exactly
how you feel about them.
Yes, but still...
Isaki's report is straight-up fire!
She's so good at tying it all together!
Isaki.
Help me with my assignment.
Huh? You don't mean Isaki?
My assignment is to write a letter
for everyone in the advanced class.
You mean I'm included in that?
Of course you are.
If I miss my chance today, I have to
wait a month, which will be too late.
So I wrote yours first.
Ushami!
H-Hey! Get your grubby mitts off me!
Isaki, sit!
No hesitation!
Just keep in mind that I'm not
as good at writing as Isaki.
Writing letters isn't about
how good or bad you are!
I'm so happy!
Hey, can I read it now?
I don't think I can wait!
S-Sure...
It's yours now, so I can't stop you.
Sweet! Thanks!
Let's see...
Thanks, Ushami...
This stuff about my bright, cheery smile
or how you think I'm considerate...
I really appreciate all
the good things you wrote about me!
I'm so happy you feel that way, Ushami!
I told you to get your hands off me!
I love you lots too, Ushami!
I know we don't see each other often,
but I'm glad you still remembered me!
Thanks, Ushami!
How could I forget someone so annoying?
What? Guess I'll have to be more annoying!
Shut up!
I can't wait for my letter from Usami.
When will I be getting mine?
I'm looking forward to it!
Usami, you use simple words
that directly convey how you feel.
Your writing is so thoughtful and sweet.
I really love it.
I've never gotten a letter before.
It's like your words
are coming alive on paper.
How wonderful.
I can tell that you pay close attention
to both me and yourself.
I've always admired
how you never admit defeat.
Uchami...
Why'd you burst into tears?
I never knew that's how you felt about me!
Man, you really love me, don't you?!
Machi, please don't cry.
If you start crying, I...
I won't be able to stop myself, either!
Hey, don't you go crying now, Isaki.
I've been holding back this whole time!
What? Karin, too?
Hah! Usami made them cry!
Tobari! Don't make me
sound like the bad guy!
It really is all your fault, Usami...
After always being so stern,
you're so kind in your letter...
She's right! What's the big idea?
You're head over heels for me!
You didn't have to say all
those nice things about me!
Cry or get angry, pick one!
Hitoma. This is my last letter.
I get one, too?
Everyone in the advanced
class includes you, Hitoma.
I'm not gonna fall
for a simple trick question like that.
Also...
Neneko Kurosawa
This is for Neneko.
She was a student this
school year, so...
Thanks, Usami.
I'll deliver this letter for you.
Thanks.
Not gonna read yours?
I'll do it when I get home.
What? Why not now?
Nope. I bet I'll cry when I do.
I guess that's true.
I've made up my mind.
All this time, I've been worried
about the reviews for my assignment.
But thanks to Usami's letter,
I've seen the light.
Instead of stressing out over details,
I need to plainly state the way I feel.
That's all I need to do in order
to stir people's emotions.
Hurry up and finish
your assignment, Isaki.
I know you can do it.
Yes! Thank you!
I'm done...
Good work! I know it must have been hard!
Thank you very much.
Nice going.
Good job.
Ichaki, you're amazing!
Th-Thank you, everyone...
Ohgami, good work.
You did your best.
Mr. Hitoma.
Thank you!
Advanced class!
A hearty congratulations to all of you!
Principal.
I've just confirmed that you've all
completed your graduation assignments.
After careful consideration, we've decided
who meets the graduation requirements!
The students graduating this year...
are more diligent than the rest,
care greatly for others,
and show deep passion for their interests.
Faced with doubts and hardship,
they persevered as a pair, hand-in-hand.
Cheerful and kind,
they learned to love themselves.
And for their graduation assignment,
from the words and ideas of tales old
and new, from around the world,
they learned to communicate,
or in other words,
express their thoughts and feelings
with greater precision than before.
For these reasons stated,
this year's graduating students...
Isaki Ohgami and Isaki Ohgami.
It'll be you two.
Once again, congratulations!
Thank you very much.
Thank you, everyone!
Next Episode:
The Misanthrope and the Comet's Pilgrimage